#### Contact

joshuafajardofrink@gmail.co m

www.linkedin.com/in/joshua-fajardo-frink-3729b1224 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Python React.js

Node.js

# Joshua Fajardo-Frink

Full stack Python, React, Angular Developer Albany

## Summary

With a decade of experience as a software engineer, web developer, and SEO strategist, I know what it takes to build a successful website from the ground to effectively nurture and convert your target market. I am experienced in responsive web development using Python, Django, Flask, React, Angular, Node, Next, Tailwind, Bootstrap, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, custom APIs, eCommerce, SEO, and cloud platforms.

I develop unique web apps/websites that drive considerably more sales, results, and leads to your business than the industry average. I have worked in many different industries such as professional services, retail, wine, technology, real estate, entertainment, and healthcare

#### Tech Stacks:

- Python, Django, Flask
- React, Angular, Vue, Next, Node, Express, Tailwind, Material, Bootstrap, jQuery
- RESTful API, 3rd party API integration
- MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL
- Azure, AWS

I meticulously manage all website projects from defining scope, market research, and concept development to your website launch and web maintenance support so you stay informed and on track every step of the way. The majority of my clients have been with me for many years because I am very passionate about web development.

My other interests include sports, music, and gaming.

## Experience

**PromGifts** 

Full-stack Web Developer
January 2018 - December 2021 (4 years)
New York, NY

 Taken part in software development life cycle (SDLC) of the tracking systems Requirements, Gathering, Analysis, Detail Design, Development, System Testing, and User Acceptance Testing and developed models in many methodologies to document existing and future processes.

Techs used: Python, Django, Flask, React, Angular, Node, jQuery, Bootstrap, MongoDB, and PostgreSQL.

DEFY Media Python Developer 2015 - 2017 (2 years) New York, NY

 Managed datasets using Panda data frames and Oracle-SQL, queried Oracle-SQL database queries from python using Python-Oracle-SQL connector and Oracle-SQL DB package to retrieve information and created Restful APIs to integrate and enhanced functionalities of the application.
 Techs used: Python, React, Angular, Node, jQuery, MongoDB, and PostgreSQL.

United Services Automobile Association Software Developer 2013 - 2014 (1 year) West Orange, NJ

 Maintained Linux hosting environment, Apache web server, and MySQL database server, and involved in developing Rest-API for the web applications using HTML, XML, CSS, JavaScript, Angular.JS, Express.JS, React JS, and JQuery, created Git repository, and added the project to GitHub.

Techs used: Angular, React, Express, jQuery, Bootstrap, MySQL, and Git.

Petco Software Engineer 2012 - 2012 (less than a year)

Norwalk, Connecticut

• Involved in the development of Web Services using SOAP for sending and getting data from the external interface in the XML format, and worked with varieties of Relational Databases (RDBMS) like SQLite, MySQL, and PostgreSQL and NoSQL DBs like MongoDB.

Techs used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, SQLite, MySQL, Apache.

## Education

Columbia University in the City of New York

Bachelor of Computer Science, Computer Science · (2006 - 2011)